저녁 맛있게 잘 먹었어요
-Thanks for the tasty dinner.
-You're welcome for a tasty dinner.
- 별말씀을 다 하시네요
- 얘들아, 뭔데 그래?
What are you guys looking at?
Ross and the most beautiful girl
in the world.
로스와 세상에서
제일 아름다운 여자
Yeah, come to Papa!
아빠가 기겁할 일이네?
I know!
알아!
Probably the only time
I'll say this...
이런 말 좀 저질이지만
그 여자 엉덩이 봤어?
...but did you see the ass on her?
What did you...?
When did you...?
너... 언제... 어떻게...
어떻게 저런 여자를 만났어?
How did you...?
How did you get a girl like that?
So what is she, like a spokesmodel?
An aerobics instructor?
내레이터 모델이야?
에어로빅 강사야?
고생물학 박사 과정인데
신생대를 전공하고 있지
Actually, she's a paleontology
doctoral candidate...
...specializing in the Cenozoic Era.
But that's, like, the easiest era.
그렇게 어려운 시대는 아니군
I've seen her at work,
but I always figured....
그 여자 일하는 걸 봤지만
내 생각엔... 크흥!
But I made her dinner.
내가 저녁 만들어주고
We had a great time.
And we're going out again tomorrow.
아주 즐거웠어
내일 또 만날 거야
Maybe her friends are betting to see
who gets the biggest geek.
누가 덜떨어진 애 데려오나
친구랑 내기한 거 아닐까?
Fine by me.
Hope she wins.
좋지, 그 여자가 이겼으면 해
Hey, we should have
a contest. Yeah.
야, 우리도 내기하자
See who can bring home
the most beautiful woman.
누가 더 예쁜 여자 데려오나
That's a good idea, Joe.
We could call it life.
좋은 생각이다만
평생과업이다
The One with the Dirty Girl
안녕, 혹시 포장지 있어?
You have any wrapping paper?
내 생일선물이야?
Is it for my birthday present?
It was your birthday months ago.
네 생일은 몇 달 전이었잖아
You said you ordered something special
and it just hadn't come yet.
뭘 주문했다더니
아직 도착 안 했니?
I have a call in about that.
그런 사건도 있었나요?
알았어
It's for Kathy. It's an early copy
of her favorite book.
사실 캐시의 생일선물이야
이 책을 좋아한대
The Velveteen Rabbit!
오! '무명벨벳토끼'
진짜 토끼로 부활하지?
When the boy's love
makes the rabbit real....
오일 바른 손으로
만지면 곤란하지
Don't touch it because
your fingers have destructive oils.
Then you'd better keep it away
from Ross' hair.
그럼 로스 머리를
더 조심해라
This is pretty rare.
How did you get that?
이런 귀한 책을
어떻게 구했어?
그야 어려울 거 있나
서점 주인들 만나보고
No big deal.
I just went to some bookstores...
...talked to some dealers, called
some of the author's grandchildren.
작가 손자들한테 전화하고
Honey, that's so sweet.
정말 기특하다
What a great way to say, "l secretly
love you, roommate's girlfriend."
룸메이트의 여자친구를
몰래 흠모하는 방법이지
It doesn't say that.
그런 뜻이 아냐
Does it?
그치?
How will it look when you get her
something incredibly meaningful...
넌 이렇게 의미심장하고
비싼 선물을 마련했는데
...and expensive, and her boyfriend,
Joey, gives her an orange?
조이는 오렌지를 준다?
I'll make sure Joey gets her
something really great.
조이한테도 멋진 걸
준비하라고 할게
It's got to be better than that book.
그 책보다 좋은 게 뭘까?
석궁이 왔다야!
Like a crossbow!
다시 한 번 죄송해요
감사합니다, 그럼
Once again, I am sorry.
Thank you. Bye.
I had to turn down a job
catering a funeral for 60 people.
60명 장례식에 쓸 요리라는데
그걸 거절하고 말았네
Oh, my God!
What happened?
세상에, 무슨 사고 났어?
Sixty guests.
문상객이 60명
Why'd you have to turn it down?
왜 거절했는데?
I don't have
the money or equipment...
돈도 없고 장비도 없고
시간도 너무 촉박해
...to handle something that big
on such short notice.
그게 한계야
Wow, what is with all the negativity?
얘 상당히 비관적이네?
You sound like "Moni-can't,"
not "Moni-can"!
'모니-깡'보다
'모니-칼'이 낫잖아
Moni-ca.
모니-카...
You've been playing around
with this catering for years.
넌 이 바닥에서 3년이 넘게
뒹굴었어, 요리사 되기 싫어?
-Do you want to be a caterer?
-I don't know.
- 글쎄?
- 좋았어! 바로 그런 패기야!
There you go!
That's the spirit!
돈이 필요하다면 내가
빌려줄게, 그냥 밀어붙여
If you need money, I will lend
you money. Just get moving!
Really? I'd need $500
for all the food and supplies.
정말? 준비하려면
5백 달러나 드는데
It's worth it if it'll get you moving.
You haven't worked in months!
좋아, 아까울 거 뭐 있겠어
너 몇 달째 놀고 있잖아
-Neither have you.
-Yes, but I'm doing this.
- 피차일반일 텐데?
- 이것도 다 사업이야
That would be great! Thank you.
이렇게 고마울 데가
- 나야
- 왔어?
-Can I borrow your apartment keys?
-Why?
아파트 키 좀 줘
왜?
You can pee here.
여기서 누면 되잖아
Yes, I can, of course.
못 눌 것도 없지
실례할게요
It's okay.
The duck's using our bathroom anyway.
어차피 우리 변기는
오리 녀석이 차지했어요
What are you getting
for her birthday?
넌 생일선물 뭐 준비했냐?
We've been dating a couple weeks.
I got to get her something?
겨우 몇 주 만났는데
선물을 줘야 되나?
그럼!
당연히 줘야지
아주 근사한 걸로
You have to get her
something really nice.
-I know!
-And not one of your coupons...
- 있다!
- 잠자리 쿠폰은 발행하지 마
...for an hour of "Joey Love."
-A crossword! Can I help?
-No.
- 크로스워드네? 도와주리?
- 싫엇!
Last week I got all
but three answers...
미안해
지난주에도 세 개 못 풀었어
혼자서 해보고 싶어
...and I want to finish one
without any help.
Fine.
알았어, 공부 좀 하자는데
영 도움을 안 주네
But you can't help me develop
my new universal language.
- 얘들아
- 어떻게 됐어?
How'd it go?
Oh, my God!
It was the best funeral ever!
세상에, 최고의 장례식이었어!
Everyone loved the food.
얼마나 맛있게 먹던지
그리고 내일 장례식이 또 있어
I even got another funeral
for tomorrow.
오늘 죽은 사람의 친구
The dead guy from today's best friend.
It's like I am the official caterer
for that accident.
장례식 공식지정
요리사 아니겠어?
Mon, I'm so happy for you!
- 정말 잘됐다
- 고마워, 요리도구 좀 샀어
Thanks. Check out
my new catering stuff.
Look!
I'm an omelet station!
봐, 오믈렛 자판기입니다!
Omelet? Made to order?
오믈렛? 주문하세요
I'll have one, please.
Plus my money.
하나 주세요
내 돈이랑 같이
I didn't realize
you needed it right away.
그렇게 빨리 갚는 거였어?
You told me to go and be a caterer.
So I went. I be'd.
요리사가 되라고 해서
임무완수하고 왔는데
이거 사느라 다 썼어
I used it to buy all this stuff.
Aborigine.
원주민!
오... 아니구나
I got another job tomorrow,
so I'll pay you back then.
하지만 내일 거기서
돈이 나올 거야
살았다, 은행원처럼
굴어서 미안해
Okay. Sorry I acted like a bank.
Aborigine.
Oh, no, I tried that already.
원주민!
아까 나왔구나
Would you like to come in?
잠깐 들어올래요?
Did Homo erectus hunt
with wooden tools?
호모에렉투스가 나무연장으로
사냥을 했던가?
According to recent findings.
최근 연구결과에 의하면
Here, Mitzi! Here, Mitzi!
먹어라, 미찌!
여기 있다!
Mitzi is...?
- 미찌의 정체는...
- 내 햄스터예요
My hamster.
I hope she's okay.
I haven't seen her in a while.
무사해야 할 텐데
요즘 통 안 보여서
Have a seat.
앉아요
Where?
Oh, hey. Do you....
저기, 혹시...
Do you have any
Cinnamon Fruit Toasties?
- 계피향 시리얼 있어요?
- 네?
Well, I do.
난 있는데
우리 집에 가서 촛불도 켜고
계피향 시리얼을 꺼내서...
Let's go back to my place,
light a couple candles...
...break open a box
of Cinnamon Fruit Toasties....
-I'd rather not.
-Oh, yeah? Why not?
사양할게요
왜요?
저기... 내 말 오해하지 말아요
그 집에선 이상한 냄새가 나요
Don't take this the wrong way...
...but your place kind of
has a weird smell.
-ls everything in the car?
-Did you settle the bill?
- 다 실었어?
- 그래, 계산은 끝났니?
아니, 이 부분이 제일 싫어
I hate this part.
Look what we almost left!
- 이걸 두고 갈 뻔했네?
- 내 거 아냐
That's not mine.
이걸 갖고 갈 뻔했네?
Look what we almost took!
Excuse me, Mrs. Burkart?
실례할게요, 버카트 부인
주방은 다 치웠어요
Well, we're all cleaned up.
좋아요
수고했어요
Good. Thank you.
And, well, there's
this small matter of the....
해결할 게 남았는데...
-Dear?
-The matter of...
- 뭐죠?
- 그러니까... 계산서요
...payment.
Jack used to handle the finances.
돈 문제는 그이가
도맡아 처리했는데
-You get it?
-No, but I made a widow cry.
받았어?
아니, 내가 과부를 울렸어
난 지옥 갈 거야
See you in hell.
You know what we should all do?
우리가 할 일이 있어
가서 뮤지컬을 보는 거야
Go see a musical.
Sure.
좋지...
You know which one?
어떤 건지 알아?
The 1996 Tony Award winner.
1996년 토니상 수상작
I mean, that one's gotta be good.
그럼 믿을 만하잖아?
Do you know the name of that one?
제목이 뭐게?
I don't know. Grease?
글쎄... 그리스?
아니
Rent?
렌트?
Yes! Rent!
고렇지! 렌트
So when do you want to go?
- 그래, 언제 갈 건데?
- 뭐? 미안, 바빠서 안돼
What? I'm sorry.
I can't, I'm busy.
나 왔다
Man, it is so hard
to shop for girls.
여자 선물 사는 게
이리도 힘들 줄이야
Yes, it is...
문방구에 가면 그렇지!
...at Office Max!
What did you get her?
뭘 샀는데?
A pen.
펜 한 자루
It's two gifts in one.
It's a pen that's also a clock.
두 가지 겸용이야
펜도 되고 시계도 돼
-You can't give her that.
-Why not?
이건 곤란해
- 왜?
- 11살이 아니니까!
She's not 11!
And it's not the seventh night
of Chanukah.
유태인 명절도 아니고!
What he means by that is,
while this is a very nice gift...
그냥 주면 좋은 선물이긴 한데
남자친구한테 받긴 좀 그렇지?
...maybe it's not something
a boyfriend gives.
Sure it is.
좋은데 뭘
She needs a pen for work.
직장에서 글을 쓰다가
이렇게 보면...
She's writing. She turns it over.
"It's time for my date with Joey!"
'와! 조이 만날 시간이네?'
All right. What did you get
for Angela Del Veccio's birthday?
좋아, 이거 봐...
안젤라 델 베키오의
생일엔 뭘 줬는데?
She didn't have one.
생일 맞은 적이 없어
For three years?
3년 동안?
Look, it's too late,
and I got an audition.
이거 봐, 너무 늦었어
오디션도 있고 쇼핑은 더 못해
I can't shop anymore.
좋아... 내가 나가서
대신 찾아볼게, 됐지?
I will go out
and try to find something for her.
Thanks, man.
고맙다
While you're at it,
could you get her a card?
간 김에 카드도 골라볼래?
Would you like me to write her
a little poem as well?
내가 시도 한 수 적어주랴?
Or just get a card
that has a poem already in it.
아예 시가 박힌 걸로 사든지
Oh, so it's a card,
but it's also a poem-holder.
그러니까 카드도 되고
시집도 되는 구나
-You have to get our money.
-She couldn't stop crying.
돈을 받아야지
울음을 안 그치잖아
With those thick glasses,
her tears look giant.
돋보기 때문에 눈물방울이
왕방울처럼 보인다니까
I know, it's tough.
쉽진 않겠지
You know what the first thing I did
after my mom's funeral was?
엄마 장례식 끝나고
내가 제일 먼저 뭘 했게?
-What?
-Pay the caterer!
- 뭔데?
- 요리사 수고비 줬다
I've had a lot of jobs.
나도 여러 직업 전전했지만
이렇게 꽁무니 빼는 사람 많아
And there are some people
who always try to get out of paying.
It's either "That massage
wasn't long enough"...
'마사지가 왜 이리 짧아?'
'그 노래는 모르겠는데?'
...or "l don't know
any of those songs"...
'밀짚모자가 너무 작잖아
이 희멀건 아가씨야! '
...or "These sombreros aren't
big enough. Bad little white girl!"
알았어
그럼 저게 연기하는 걸까?
So you think she's faking?
There weren't any tears
till you showed her the bill.
청구서 보기 전엔
안 울었잖아
She sounded pretty upset to me.
많이 상심한 것 같아
She seems fine now.
지금은 멀쩡한데?
So you just left?
Her place was really that bad?
그냥 나왔다고?
집이 그렇게 엉망이든?
You throw your jacket on a chair
at the end of the day.
일 끝나고 들어오면
소파에 재킷을 던지잖아?
Like that, only instead of a chair,
it's a pile of garbage.
소파는 어디 가고
쓰레기만 있더라
And instead of a jacket,
it's a pile of garbage.
재킷은 어디 가고
쓰레기만 있더라고
And instead of the end of the day,
it's the end of time...
포근한 휴식은 어디 가고
쓰레기 대군만 득시글거려
...and garbage is all
that has survived.
-Here.
-Wow. Thanks.
- 됐다
- 고마워
So what happened?
그래서 어떻게 됐어?
Nothing.
I had to get out of there.
어떻게 되긴
그냥 나왔는데
그럼 다음 번엔
너희 집으로 가
Next time, you take her
to your place.
그럴까 했는데 우리 집에서
이상한 냄새가 난대
I tried that.
She says it has a weird smell.
-What kind of smell?
-I don't know. Soap?
- 무슨 냄새?
- 글쎄, 비누?
-Listen, you like this girl, right?
-Yeah.
- 어쨌든 그 여자 좋아하지?
- 그럼
-You want to see her again?
-Yeah.
- 또 만나고 싶지?
- 맞아
So you're going to have
to do it in the mess!
그럼 쓰레기더미에서 해!
Yeah, okay. You're right.
그래, 네 말이 옳다
I mean, who cares about
a little sloppiness?
조금 지저분한 게 대수야?
마냥 편하고 좋잖아?
-It's endearing, really.
-All right!
그렇지! 그 예쁜이
돼지를 잡는 거야!
Now you go get that beautiful pig!
I just spent the entire
afternoon looking for a present...
그래, 좋아
오후 내내 그 토끼보다
나은 선물을 찾아 헤맸어
...for Kathy that would be
better than the rabbit.
Any luck?
- 찾았니?
- 그럼
Yeah, I found this great place
called "lnvisible Things for Kathy."
투명한 선물만 전문으로
취급하는 데가 있더라
Can you give me a hand
with all this stuff?
이거 같이 포장할까?
Just return the book,
let Joey give her the clock pen...
그 책은 돌려주고
시계 펜보다 안 좋은 걸
찾아보는 게 어때, 가령...
...and you get her
something worse than that...
...Iike a regular pen.
그냥 보통 펜으로
She's really going
to love this, you know?
이게 딱이야, 알아?
The bottom line is,
I want her to have it...
난 꼭 주고 싶다고
...even if I don't get to be
the one who gives it to her.
다른 사람이
주더라도 괜찮아
Honey, that's so sweet.
순해빠져선...
그래?
구질구질한 게 아니고?
You don't think it's just pathetic?
Oh, "pathetic"!
맞다, 구질구질!
야, 10분 전인데
너 한참 찾았잖아
I've been looking all over for you.
-Where?
-Our place. The hall.
- 어디서?
- 우리 집, 복도...
I got something for her.
쓸만한 걸 찾았어
It's a book.
책이야
A book?
책?
허걱! 책도 되고
금고도 되냐?
Is it a book that's also a safe?
It's a book that's just a book.
아니, 그냥 책이라고
캐시가 어렸을 때 즐겨 읽던
'무명벨벳토끼' 초판본이지
It's the Velveteen Rabbit.
It was her favorite as a kid.
So just let me know
if she likes it, okay?
아마 좋아할 거야
You got it. Thanks for doing this.
I owe you one.
그래, 정말 고맙다
신세 한 번 졌다
There wasn't any change
from that twenty, was there?
야! 20달러에서
잔돈 안 남았냐?
No, it came out to an even twenty.
아니, 우수리 없이
딱 20달러다
Wow. That's almost
as much as a new book.
이런, 그 돈이면
새 책도 사겠다
-You didn't get the money?
-Maybe I can try at intermission?
- 아직 못 받았지?
- 막간에 시도해볼까?
You know what?
Let's just go.
모르겠다, 그냥 가자
안돼, 계산이 아직
안 끝났잖아!
We're not leaving till we get paid!
I don't know
who she thinks she is.
정말 황당한 여자네?
I talked to the florist.
She didn't get paid either.
꽃집에도 돈을
안 준 모양이더라
Or the limo driver, or the priest, and he
can get the dead guy damned for all eternity.
리무진 운전사에 신부까지
죽은 사람은 꼭 지옥 간다
Well, I'm not going back out there.
난 이제 안 들어가
Fine. Enough is enough!
더는 못 참아
Hey, widow?
보세요, 과부 아줌마
Widow?
과부 아줌마?
잠깐 조용히 해욧!
Excuse me? Excuse me!
Thanks. Clearly this is
a very, very hard time for you.
고마워요
물론 힘드신 건 알지만
But we provided a service,
and we deserve to be paid...
저희가 제공한 서비스를 꼴깍
삼켰으면 대가를 지불하셔야죠
...because you ate that service.
We are not leaving here until
we are paid every penny, because...
돈 받을 때까지 못 나가요
저희는 파트타임이라
달리 갈 데도 없다구요
...we're part-time caterers
and we have no place else to go.
All right. I'll get my bag.
- 좋아요, 지갑 가져오죠
- 그러세요
Good.
I'm going to leave some cards here.
명함 몇 장 놓고 갈게요
Please think of us
for your next event.
앞으로도 자주 이용해주세요
So you want to come inside?
들어갈래요?
Yes.
좋지요...
Yes, I do.
네, 찬성입니다
I'll be right back.
Make yourself comfortable.
금방 올게요
편하게 있어요
Guess who?
누구~게?
Department of Sanitation?
공중위생과 직원?
It's me.
나예요
아!
What?
왜요?
Oh, Cheryl!
오, 셰릴!
이게 뭐지?
뭐야!
안돼요!
-It's my hamster! It's Mitzi!
-Oh, my God!
내 햄스터!
미찌야...
정말 미안해요
너무 겁이 나서
I'm so sorry.
I must have freaked out.
세상에, 미찌가 아니네
Thank God it's not Mitzi!
It's just a rat.
그냥 쥐예요
I did it!
해냈어!
I finished it!
I did it all by myself!
완성이야!
혼자 다 풀었어!
And there's nobody to hug.
안을 사람이 없네?
Move!
안녕
Hey, you guys!
얘들아! 크로스워드를
혼자 풀었어, 안아 줘
I finished it all by myself!
Hug me.
잘했다!
-Congratulations.
-Thank you.
- 축하해
- 고마워
How did it go?
- 일은 잘됐어?
- 굉장했지
The widow wouldn't pay,
so Phoebe yelled at her till she did.
피비가 싸워서 겨우
돈을 받아냈지 뭐야
I'm a hard-ass.
이 독종을 물로 봐?
And I'm a wuss.
We should be partners.
난 호구고
동업할까?
Hard-ass and wuss.
We could fight crime.
그래, '독종과 호구'
범죄 소탕에 나설까?
Wait a minute, Phoebe.
잠깐, 피비?
We should be partners.
진짜로 동업하자
We should be catering partners.
출장요리 파트너
You're not working now,
and we have a great time together.
넌 지금 놀고 있고
함께 일하면 즐겁잖아
좋아
I cook and you take care
of the money.
난 요리 담당
넌 재정 담당
50년대 마누라를 얻었네?
It'll be like
I have a wife in the 50s!
- 나야
- 그래, 반응은 어땠어
How did she like the gift?
아주 뻑 가더라, 모니카랑
레이첼한테 자랑하는 중이야
She loved it.
She's showing the girls right now.
Yeah? That's great.
그거 잘됐다
그나저나 너한테
송구해서 어쩌냐
I got to tell you...
...I feel bad taking credit
for this, because...
...am I going to get
a lot of credit for this!
이번에 점수 왕창 따버렸다
- 생일 축하해요
- 고마워요
-Happy birthday.
-Thank you.
You know, Chandler got you
a gift too.
저기, 챈들러도 선물이 있대
No, he didn't.
선물은 무슨!
Yeah, he did. Look,
it's right there on the counter.
너도 준비했잖아
여기 있네, 호호호!
Happy birthday.
생일 축하드려요
I'm sorry.
너무 약소합니다
You really didn't have to.
무슨 말씀을
그냥 보기엔 펜이지만
돌리면 시계도 된다네요
You think it's just a pen, but you
turn it over and it's also a clock.
No, this is great!
너무 좋은데요?
-Thank you, Chandler.
-Oh, yeah.
고마워요, 챈들러
Want to go to bed?
침소로 들까?
I'll be in, in a minute.
- 금방 들어갈게
- 그래
참! 그리고...
쿠폰 잘 챙겨
Don't forget your coupon.
Good night.
잘 자요
Thank you for the gift.
선물 고마워요
I just knew that
sometimes when you're writing...
정신없이 글을 쓰다 보면
시간을 잊는 수가 많으니까
...you don't always
know the exact time.
No, I didn't mean the pen.
Thank you for the book.
펜이 아니에요
책 고맙다구요
The book?
책이라면?
The Velveteen Rabbit?
'무명벨벳토끼'
내 느낌이 맞을 거예요
I have a feeling you had
something to do with it.
What do you mean?
무슨 얘기죠?
조이는 내가 토끼와 치즈를
좋아해서 이 책을 주는 거래요
When Joey gave it to me he said:
"This is because I know you like
rabbits, and I know you like cheese."
Thanks. I love it.
고마워요, 맘에 들어요
여간해선 찾기 힘든 건데
I know how hard
it must have been for you to find.
뭐 그냥...
In case you missed that,
that sound was, "Oh, well."
못 들었을지도 모르니까
한 번 더, 뭐 그냥...
You must really like Joey
to go to all that trouble.
정말 대단한 우정이에요
그런 수고를 감수하다니
Oh, yeah. He's my
그럼요, 쟤는...
He's my best friend.
둘도 없는 친구죠
-Well....
-Good night.
- 그럼...
- 쉬세요
Hey, that coupon expires, you know.
쿠폰은 사용기한이 있어
You don't know me.
I'm Monica Geller, Ross' sister.
안녕하세요
전 모니카 겔러라고
로스 오빠 동생이에요
You know, it's too bad
that didn't work out.
그렇게 끝나서
나도 유감이에요
어쨌든 이 아파트
얘기를 들었는데
Anyway, he told me
about your apartment.
Well, I couldn't sleep
thinking about it.
밤에 잠을 통 못 자요
So would it be okay
if I cleaned it?
그래서 말인데...
청소 좀 해도 되겠죠?
싫어요?
I won't be able to sleep.
잠이 안 온다니깐?